ARTHUR MODYMAN IV

Everett, WA 98201 | 206 627-0422 | arthurmodymaniv@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/arthur-m-16a8a149/ **Resume Page/Portfolio pieces: https://artresume.web.app/ | github.com/ArtimusMaximus

Web Developer

SUMMARY QUALIFICATION

Javascript developer with over 1.5 years of front & back-end web application production and 5+ years in static web development. I am a highly motivated, flexible, consummate professional that takes pride in what they do. Always on the learning path to improve current skills and acquire new ones; relevant to web development and programming overall.

CORE COMPETENCIES

Front End Back End NodeJS @16.11.1, ExpressJS React @18.2.0 w/hooks, JSX **REST APIs, CRUD applications** Javascript ES6 Mongoose MongoDB API HTML5, JSON Schemas Authorization w/Passport, OAuth2 CSS3, Tailwind, Bootstrap data fetching/XHR requests Databases Version control systems & Work Flows MongoDB (NoSQL) Git Slack, Zoom, MS Teams SQL Firebase Firestore & Realtime Database OTHER TECHNICAL USES

Adobe Suite – Light Room, Photoshop, Premiere | Microsoft Word | Reaper Digital Audio Work station

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Web Developer | Pacific Panorama LLC | Seattle, WA

Jul 2021 – Present

⇒ Front-end Web Applications Developer – Javascript, React, HTML, CSS, Firebase, MongoDB, NextJS

3D modeler, Photographer | Pacific Panorama LLC | Seattle, WA

Jul 2020 - July 2021

- Produce High Dynamic Range (HDR) photos, flash ambient mix photos (flambient), and aerial images (drone).
- Provide 3D virtual tours via Matterport PRO2 for commercial & industrial Real Estate

Webmaster | Northtown Company | Huntington Beach, CA

Sep 2010 – 2016

- Oversee the update/maintenance of the company's static website
- ⇒ 50+ product web pages implemented,
- ⇒ Product catalog production, graphic designs, Material Safety Data Sheets updated for industry compliance
- Optimized administrative duties for incoming sales orders, sales order processing, sales order confirmations, client confirmations of price adjustments/availability
- ⇒ Liaise with shipping firms to handle the logistics for outbound warehouse shipments to warehouse/job site.

EARLIER PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE: 2003-2017

Bar Manager (3 yrs.) | Patina Restaurant Group | Cerritos, CA

Head Bartender (5 yrs.) | Patina Restaurant Group | Cerritos, CA

Banquet Server/ Bartender (3 yrs.) | Tangata Restaurant PRG | Santa Ana, CA

Entertainer (2 yrs.) | The Walt Disney Company | Anaheim, CA

PRG work locations: Segerstrom Center for the Arts | Park Privè | Cerritos Performing Arts Center

Everett, WA 98201 | 206 627-0422 | arthurmodymaniv@gmail.com

CONTINUED

Continued Education: TRAINING & CERTIFICATIONS from MOOC's (2021-2022)

Learning Path: Become a Back-End Web Developer LinkedIn Learning	2022
Learning Node.js LinkedIn Learning	2022
Node.js Essential Training LinkedIn Learning	2022
Node.js Testing and Code Quality LinkedIn Learning	2022
Databases for Node.js Developers LinkedIn Learning	2022
Building RESTful APIs with Node.js and Express LinkedIn Learning	2021
Express Essential Training LinkedIn Learning	2022
Programming Foundations: Web Security LinkedIn Learning	2022
Node.js Securing RESTful APIs LinkedIn Learning	2022
HTTP Essential Training LinkedIn Learning	2022
Learning npm Node Package Manager LinkedIn Learning	2022
Advanced npm LinkedIn Learning	2022
Node.js Microservices LinkedIn Learning	2022
Learning Path: Become a MERN Stack JavaScript Developer LinkedIn Learning	2021
React.js Essential Training LinkedIn Learning	2022
Building a Website with Node.js and Express.js LinkedIn Learning	2022
Learning MongoDB LinkedIn Learning	2022
Learning Full-Stack JavaScript Development: MongoDB, Node, and React LinkedIn Learning	2022
Node.js Security LinkedIn Learning	2021
Python for Everybody Specialization Coursera	2021
Programming for Everybody (Getting Started with Python) Coursera	2021
Python Data Structures Coursera	2021
Using Python to Access Web Data Coursera	2021
Using Databases with Python Coursera	2021
Capstone: Retrieving, Processing, and Visualizing Data with Python Coursera	2021
The Complete Modern JavaScript Master Class 2021 Udemy	2021
JavaScript: Best Practices for Data LinkedIn Learning	2022
Learning Functional Programming with JavaScript ES6+ LinkedIn Learning	2021
MERN Essential Training LinkedIn Learning	2022
React: Working with APIs LinkedIn Learning	2022
React.js: Building an Interface LinkedIn Learning	2021
React.js Single Page Applications LinkedIn Learning	2022
React: Creating and Hosting a Full-Stack Site LinkedIn Learning	2022
Creating a Serverless Application Using React in AWS LinkedIn Learning	2021
M320: Data Modeling MongoDB University	2022
M220 JS: MongoDB for JavaScript Developers MongoDB University	2022
Front-End Web UI Frameworks: Bootstrap 4 Coursera	2021
(all certifications available on my personal page, links in footer: https://ivthe.art)	

FORMAL EDUCATION

Orange Coast College, Costa Mesa, CA

Sep 2003 – Dec 2008

Associate of Arts – AA, Information Technology

PROJECTS - (all projects available on my personal page: https://artresume.web.app/)

Claims.gifts (https://claims.gifts) – Full stack Developer

- Claims.gifts is a gift exchange consolidation web application. Similar to a gift registry, but all participants and their gifts are in one place for easier management of larger groups of people
- Demonstrates OAuth2, real time database, full stack development

Beach front rental page (https://otwrentals-c3f25.web.app) - Front End Developer

- React single page application
- Demonstration of reusable components, original design

Contact: Art Modyman - E: ArthurModymanIV@gmail.com T: 206 627 0422